-Does everybody hate these shoes? -Yeah.
你们都觉得这双鞋很丑吗？ 对
But nobody will focus on that if you wear that towel-dress.
别担心，没有人会注意的 只要你穿着那件浴巾装
Tell him.
你跟他说吧
It's her first day at this new job. You shouldn't start with her.
这是她履新职的第一天 你不该一早就开她玩笑
All right. I suppose I can wait a day.
好吧，我可以等到晚上再说
-What are you doing Friday? -Why?
你星期五有节目吗？ 干嘛？
Come to my weird cousin Albert's bachelor party.
你得来参加我的怪堂哥 艾勃特的告别单身派对
You know,he's the botanist?
你知道，他是植物学家
Oh,God!
老天
Botanists are such geeks.
植物学家都神神经经的
Is that a dinosaur tie?
那是恐龙领带吗？
Morning!
早安
Rach,I'm here with the purses!
瑞秋，我拿皮包来了
It must take you forever to find your keys.
找钥匙就要找老半天吧
Thank you,Pheebs.
谢谢，菲比
You're welcome. Please want the one with the turtles.
不客气，拜托你用 这个乌龟包包
No,turtles scare me. I don't need that today.
不，乌龟让我害怕 今天尤其不是时候
Honey,just relax. It's gonna be fine.
亲爱的，别紧张，没问题的
Why don't I come and take you to lunch?
我过来跟你一起吃午饭吧？
Thank you! But Mark's taking me out.
谢了，但马克要带我去吃饭
Mark? Is that the same Mark that helped you get the job?
马克？就是那个 帮你找工作的马克？
It's like a "good luck on your first day" thing.
对，算是祝我工作顺利
Is this a lunch box?
那是午餐盒吗？
No,a purse. And there's a thermos in it.
不，是皮包 里面还有个热水瓶
-So can you make it on Friday? -What?
你星期五能来吗？ 什么？
I think so. Why am I invited to this again?
我想可以吧 可是你为什么要请我呢？
Apparently,Albert has no friends.
显然艾勃特没有朋友
He's excited about the bachelor party.
他对告别单身派对充满期待
He's only getting married so he can see a stripper.
我想他是为了看 脱衣舞娘才结婚的
A stripper at a bachelor party. That is so cliche.
请脱衣舞娘参加告别单身派对 你们真是老套
Why don't you guys get a magician?
为什么不请魔术师？
If he can open my beer with his butt-cheeks,then all right.
如果魔术师可以用臀部 给我开啤酒，那就行
The One With All the Jealousy
本集播出：“嫉妒的情人”
-=BT之家DRM小组 http://bbs.btbbt.com=- 河马压缩制作 本字幕为河马根据R3DVD OCR得来
She's having lunch with him? Lunch with him?
她要跟她吃午饭？ 跟他吃午饭？
You should've seen him hug her when she got the job!
你该看看她被录取时 是怎么拥抱他的
And he's really good-looking.
而且他相貌堂堂
-What am I gonna do? -You don't do anything.
我该怎么办？ 不怎么办
IKeep it inside. Learn how to hide your feelings.
放在心里 学着隐藏你的感情
Don't cry out loud.
不要大呼小叫
Guess who has an audition for a Broadway musical?
猜猜谁得到了百老汇 音乐剧的试演机会？
I wanna say you,but it seems like such an easy answer.
我本来要说是你 不过这个答案好像太容易了
It is me!
就是我
It's a musical version of A Tale of Two Cities.
这是音乐剧版的“双城记”
So I think I'm gonna sing "New York,New York"...
我想我要唱“纽约，纽约”
...and "I Left My Heart in San Francisco."
和“我把心留在旧金山”
Joey,I don't think you get to pick the cities.
乔伊，我想轮不到你来挑城市
What?
什么？
Mr. Dickens gets to pick them.
这是狄更斯先生的权利
Who?
谁？
I'll get you the Cliff Notes.
我拿克里夫手集给你
The what?
什么？
The abridgment.
简易文学读本
The what?
什么？
Then the style number...
型号
...the invoice number and the shipping date.
发货号码…和出货日期
Good. Any questions so far?
很好，有问题吗？
What kind of discount do we get?
我们有多少折扣？
Twenty percent.
八折
I love this job!
我爱死这份工作了
-My first call! -Here,let me.
我的第一通电话 来，让我代劳
Rachel Greene's line. May I help you?
瑞秋葛林，需要我效劳吗？
Hi,is Rachel there?
嗨，瑞秋在吗？
-And who may I say is calling? -This is Ross.
请问是哪一位？ 我是罗斯
Ross of...?
哪位罗斯？
Of "Ross and Rachel."
“罗斯和瑞秋”的罗斯
Hi,it's Mark.
嗨，我是马克
-Hey,Mark. -Hey.
嘿，马克 嘿
Hold on a second. It's Ross.
等一下 好
Hi,honey.
嗨，亲爱的
What's Mark doing answering your phone?
马克怎么会替你接电话？
Oh,he's just goofing around.
他只是在瞎混罢了
Oh,that's funny.
有意思
Why isn't he goofing around in his own office?
他干嘛不在自己办公室瞎混？
This is his office too. I told you, we're Joanna's two assistants.
这里就是他办公室，我说过 我们是乔安娜的两个助理
Why does Joanna need two assistants?
乔安娜为什么需要两个助理？
How lazy is she?
她很懒吗？
Oh,my God! What did I just do?
我的天，我做了什么？
I just shipped 3000 bras to Personnel!
我刚把三千副胸罩 送到人事部去了
I gotta go! Mark,I need you!
我要挂电话了 马克，我需要你
Okay! Bye-bye!
好，再见
I'm sorry,sweetie. I was just trying to
对不起，甜心，我只是要…
I was dialing another number.
我只是要打下一个电话
I got changed in 30 seconds so you could be alone with him.
我30秒钟换好衣服 就是让你跟他独处
You better go for it.
你最好赶快展开攻势
I'm not going for anything.
我不要展开什么攻势
Well,if you don't,I will.
你不要的话，我要
Would you please go?
拜托你走吧？
'Night,Mon.
晚安，摩妮卡
'Night,Julio.
晚安，胡利欧
Someone left their book here.
胡利欧，有人把书忘在这里了
Actually,that is mine.
老实说，那是我的书
What are you reading?
你在看什么书？
Flowers of Evil,by Baudelaire. Have you read it?
波特来尔的“恶之华” 你看过没有？
Have I read it?
我看过没有？
No. Are you enjoying it?
没有，你喜欢吗？
I thought I would, but the translation's no good.
我本来以为我会喜欢 不过翻译得不好
You're a poet and you don't know it.
你是诗人，居然不懂
Actually,l....
其实，我…
I am a poet.
我是诗人
So you do know it.
那你一定懂了
So what kind of things do you write about?
你都写些什么？
Things that move me:
写一些让我感动的事物
The shadow of a tree...
婆娑树影
...a child laughing...
童稚笑容
...or this lip.
或这片嘴唇
Mine?
我的？
Right here?
这里？
I could write an epic poem about this lip.
我可以为这片嘴唇写一部史诗
How would that go?
要怎么写？
Well,it didn't rhyme...
虽然没有押韵…
...but I liked it.
不过我喜欢
You've got to pick a pocket or two...
你们得扒一、两个钱包
...boys
孩子们…
You've got to pick a pocket...
你得扒一、两个…
... or two
钱包…
Lovely.
真好
Just lovely.
太好了
Really? Thanks.
真的？谢谢
We definitely want to see you for the callback on Saturday.
乔伊，我们非常希望 星期六再看到你
Excellent!
太好了
I'll be there.
我会来的
Don't forget to bring your jazz shoes for the dance audition.
别忘了带你的爵士舞鞋 来参加舞蹈试演
My agent said that it wasn't a dancing part.
我的经纪人说 这个角色不必跳舞
All the roles gotta dance a little.
所有的角色都要跳一点舞
But with your dance background, it'll be a piece of cake.
但以你的舞蹈背景 小意思罢了
"Three years of modern dance with Twyla Tharp"?
追随妥拉萨普 学习三年现代舞？
"Five years with the American Ballet Theatre"?
在美国芭蕾舞团待了五年？
Everybody lies on their resume,okay?
谁的履历表不灌水？
I wasn't one of the Zoom kids either.
我也没有演过ZOOM
Well,can you,like,dance at all?
你到底会不会跳舞？
Yeah,I can dance. You know....
我会跳舞，你知道…
What is that?
这是干什么？
Sure,it looks stupid now. There's no music playing.
现在看起来很蠢 因为没有放音乐
I have to get that. But,no,no.
我得去接电话 不过，不要…
Hi.
嗨
Listen,I'm in need of a stripper and I was told that you do that.
听我说，我需要个脱衣舞娘 我听说你是跳脱衣舞的
Let me ask you this. What do you do for the extra hundred?
我问你，你多收一百块 可以额外提供什么服务？
So would I have to provide the grapes?
那我要提供葡萄吗？
Hi.
嗨
How was last night with Julio,senorita?
你昨晚跟胡利欧 约会的情况怎么样，小姐？
It was amazing. He's sexy and smart, which makes him even sexier.
简直不可思议，他性感又聪明 这让他显得更性感
Last night we were fooling around...
我得告诉你 昨晚我们亲热的时候…
...and all of a sudden he stops to write a poem.
突然之间，他停下来写诗…
Get out! I couldn't stop if a meteor hit me.
少来了，我就算被 陨石打中也停不下来
We have our stripper, a "Miss Crystal Chandelier."
我们请了脱衣舞娘 “水晶吊灯小姐”
Name a kid that,what do you expect them to grow up to be?
给小孩取这种名字 长大了还能做什么？
But he forgot to take the poem with him.
但他忘了把这首诗带走
I am totally dense about poetry, but I think this is pretty good.
我看不懂诗 不过我觉得这是一首好诗
Check it out.
你们看看
"The Empty Vase. Translucent beauty"
“空花瓶” 半透明的美
To yourself.
不要念出来
You know,that's pretty good.
写得很好
Yeah,I think so too. Phoebe?
对，我也觉得，菲比？
Great! I'm so glad you guys like it!
太棒了 我真高兴你们都喜欢
-I gotta go to work. -I'm not done.
我得去上班了 我还没看完
Give it back when you're through.
看完再还给我
-See you guys. -Bye-bye.
回头见 再见
Oh,my God! Oh,my God! Poor Monica!
我的天…可怜的摩妮卡
What? What? What?
怎么了？…
He was with her when he wrote this poem!
他在跟她亲热的时候写这首诗
"My vessel so lovely, with nothing inside"?
我的花瓶如此美丽 内里空无一物
"Now that I've touched you, you seem emptier still"?
如今我伸手触摸 你看似更加空洞
He thinks Monica's empty. She's the empty vase!
她觉得摩妮卡很空洞 她是个空花瓶
You really think he meant that?
你真的觉得他是这个意思？
Totally.
一点都没错
Oh,God! And she seems so happy too.
老天，她看起来好幸福
Done.
看完了
Do you have the Ralph Lauren file?
你有圣罗兰的档案吗？
Oh,yeah,sure! It's right
当然有，就在
What's that?
那是什么？
It's from Ross. It's a Love Bug.
是罗斯送的，爱的金龟
Somebody wants people to know you have a boyfriend.
他想向全世界宣告 你已经名花有主了
That's not what he's doing.
他不是这个意思
He's just really romantic.
他只是非常浪漫罢了
Excuse me. Are you Rachel Greene?
对不起，你是瑞秋格林吗？
One,two,three.
1、2、3
Congratulations on your first week At your brand-new job
恭喜你履新职的第一周
It won't be long Before you're the boss
要不了多久你就会当老板了
And you know who will be there To support you
你知道到时候 谁会支持你
Your one and only boyfriend
就是你唯一的男朋友
It's nice to have a boyfriend!
有男朋友真好
Your loyal,loving boyfriend,Ross!
你忠心、深情的男友，罗斯
I'm hurt! I'm actually hurt...
我伤心，我真地很伤心…
...that you'd think I'd send those things out of anything but love.
你居然以为我送那些东西 不是出于对你的爱
Hurt!
伤心
All right,I get it. You're hurt!
好，我懂了，你很伤心
Can't a guy send a barbershop quartet...
男人不能请理发店四重唱…
...to his girlfriend's office anymore?
到女朋友的办公室吗？
Oh,please! It was so obvious...
拜托，罗斯 这实在太明显了
...Iike you were marking your territory.
你好像在划定地盘
You might as well have just come in and peed around my desk!
你干脆到办公室来 在我的桌子周围撒尿好了
I would never do that.
我绝对不会这么做
Look,I know what's going on here.
听我说，我知道这是怎么回事
Mark explained it all to me. He said this is what you guys do.
马克都跟我解释过了 他说你们男人就是这样
Well,if Mark said that, then Mark's an idiot.
如果马克这么说 那马克就是白痴
Mark's a genius.
马克是个天才
Why? How? How is he a genius?
为什么？怎么说？ 他为什么会是天才？
Don't you see what's happening?
你还看不出来吗？
Instead of hitting on her now, he's becoming her confidante.
他没有勾引她 反而当了她的手帕交
Now he's gonna be the guy she goes to, to complain about you.
现在她就会跑去跟他抱怨你
What am I gonna do?
我该怎么办？
Why don't you send her a musical bug?
何不送她一个音乐金龟？
No,you already did that.
不，你已经送过了
You're gonna have to go there yourself now.
你得亲自过去
Make a few surprise visits.
偶尔让她惊喜一下
I don't know,guys.
我不知道
Fine,don't do anything. Sit and talk to us.
很好，不要轻举妄动 坐着跟我们聊天
Meanwhile,she is talking to him about you.
这时候她正在跟她谈你
And he's being Mr. Joe Sensitive.
他对她体帖入微
She's thinking,"Maybe he's the guy for me because he understands me."
她在想“也许他就是我的伴侣 他这么了解我”
And before you know it, she's with him.
你还没搞清楚状况 她就跟他在一起了
And you'll be all,"Oh,man!"
你就会说“老天”
And he'll be all,"Yes!"
他会说“太棒了”
And us,we'll be like,"Oh,dude!"
我们都会说“傻瓜”
And pretty soon you'll be like:
很快你就会说…
"Hi."
“嗨”
And,"Well,I can't go. Rachel and Mark might be there."
还有“我不能去 瑞秋和马克可能在那里”
And we'll be like,"Man,get over it! It's been four years!"
我们会说“忘了吧 已经四年了”
He paints quite a picture, doesn't he?
他说得活灵活现，不是吗？
Here's the Shelley Segal stuff for December.
这是雪丽席格12月的设计
Wait,I've got something for you.
等等，我有东西要给你
It's okay. Rachel knows.
没关系，瑞秋知道
Yeah,but even so
对，但就算是这样…
I can't help it. I'm just crazy about you.
我控制不了，我为你疯狂
Oh,that is so sweet!
你真会讲话
I know I'm Mr. Inappropriate today, but it's just so tough.
我知道我老是做不得体的事 但是这真的好难
I see you walking around, and I want to touch and hold you....
看着你走来走去 我好想把你抱在怀里
Come on,no one's around. Just kiss me.
来，这里没有人，吻我吧
All right,that's it! Get off of her!
好了，够了，放开她
What is going on?
怎么回事？
What's going on? I'll tell you what's going on!
怎么回事？ 我告诉你这是怎么回事
I have been down in your store for 20 minutes,trying to get a tie.
我在你们公司 找领带找了20分钟
What do I have to do to get some service?
要怎么样才有人来服务我？
Hi,Rach.
嗨，瑞秋
Joey Tribbiani?
乔伊特里班尼
I've got a problem.
现在出了问题
I just got a call from my dance captain.
舞蹈领队打电话来
He's having a relationship crisis and can't leave Long lsland.
他感情出现危机 不能离开长岛
Does that mean the audition's off?
这表示试演取消了吗？
Seeing as you've got the most experience...
既然你的经验丰富
... I want you to teach these dancers the combination.
我希望你来带舞者动作
What?
什么？
Come on,it's easy. You know,it's hand,hand...
好啦，很简单嘛 你知道，就是手…
... head,head...
头…
... up,pas de bourree, pas de bourree...
抬起来…不要挤在一起…
... big turn here,rond de jambe....
大旋转…腿转圈…
Slide,step,step...
滑过来，一步，再一步…
...and jazz hands!
爵士手势
So that's,"Steppity-step and jazz hands."
这么说是踏步舞步和爵士手势
Have fun.
跳得高兴点
Bye.
再见
What are you wrapping?
你在包什么？
Look what I got Julio.
看我送胡利欧什么？
It's a vase.
是个花瓶
Just like the one in the poem.
就像他那首诗
Not exactly like the one in the poem.
不完全跟那首诗一样
What do you mean?
此话怎讲？
Remember how you said you were really dense about poetry?
记得你说过你不会看诗吗？
So I'm just an empty vase?
这么说我只是个空洞的花瓶？
What?
什么？
So,I don't read as many important books as you do.
好，我不像你那样常看名著
And I don't write trick poems that aren't about what they seem.
我也不写表里不一的怪诗
And I get excited about stupid stuff...
我喜欢愚蠢的东西
...Iike when my People magazine comes...
就像我的时人杂志来的时候…
...and the new "Hold Everything" catalog.
还有“抓住一切”的 型录来的时候…
But that doesn't mean I'm empty. I care about things. Friends and family.
但这不表示我是空洞的 我关心我的家人和朋友
You have no right to judge me! You don't even know me!
你没有权利批判我 你根本不了解我
The poem is not about you.
这首诗讲的不是你
What?
什么？
"The Empty Vase" is not about you.
“空花瓶”讲的不是你
My baby preciosa....
我亲爱的宝贝…
You make me so sad that you would think this.
你居然这么想，我好难过
I'm sorry. It's....
对不起，这…
My friend Phoebe said
我朋友菲比说…
It's about all women.
这是讲所有的女人
Well...
应该是说…
...all American women.
全美国的女人
You feel better now?
释怀了没有？
All right,let's do it.
好，来吧
What was that?
那是什么玩意儿？
It's the best I could get out of them.
他们最多只能跳到这个程度
Well,people!
各位…
People,people,people!
Let's try it again. And this time, everybody watch Joey.
我们再试一次 这次大家好好看着乔伊
Show 'em how it's done.
教他们怎么跳
Count it off,Mack.
弹琴，麦克
“中央咖啡厅”
Did you have fun at the bachelor party last night?
你昨晚参加告别单身派对 玩得开心吗？
Look what I got! See,she's dressed,right?
看我拿到什么？ 看，她穿着衣服，对吗？
And then you click it, and uh-oh,she's naked!
然后按一下 她裸体了
And then you click it again and she's dressed.
然后再按一下 她又穿上衣服了
She's a business woman walking down the street.
她是个做生意的女人 走在大街上
She's window shopping, and oh,she's naked!
她在逛橱窗 哦，她裸体了
I'm gonna spend some alone time with the pen.
我要跟这只笔独处一阵子
I'm sorry. I was an idiot.
对不起，我是个白痴
A big idiot.
大白痴
It's just, you have to realize...
你必须了解…
...this Mark thing is hard for me.
我很难接受马克这件事…
Why is it hard? We've been together for almost a year now.
为什么？我们在一起快一年了
Well,I was with Carol for,like,eight years.
我跟卡洛在一起八年了
And I lost her.
而我失去了她
And now,if it's possible, I think I love you even more.
现在，如果有这个可能 我想我爱你比爱她更深
So it's hard for me to believe I'm not gonna...
所以我很难相信我不会…
...well,that someone else isn't gonna take you away.
别人不会把你夺走…
Let it be me. Let it be me!
让我夺走她吧…
Honey,that's very sweet.
亲爱的，你的话好窝心
It just seems to me,though, that if two people love each other...
我只是觉得 如果两个人彼此相爱
...and trust each other, like we do...
彼此信任，像我们这样
...there's no reason to be jealous.
就没有理由嫉妒
I gotta get going.
我得走了
Bye,Chandler.
再见，钱德
This pen's getting kind of boring. Can you pick me up some porn?
这枝笔有点无聊了 可以帮我拿几本色情杂志吗？
Where you going?
你要去哪里？
I've gotta go pick up Ben for a play-date this afternoon.
我得去接班 带他跟别人出去玩
With who?
跟谁？
Just this woman I met last night at the party.
跟我昨晚在派对上认识的女人
There was a woman at?
昨晚派对的女人…
The stripper?
脱衣舞娘？
You have a play-date with a stripper?
你跟脱衣舞娘一起出去玩？
Man,I gotta get a kid!
老天，我得生个孩子才行
We started talking after she did her thing...
她跳玩脱衣舞之后 我们开始聊天
...and she's got a boy about Ben's age.
她有个和班年龄相仿的儿子
So we're gonna take the kids to a Gymboree class.
我们要带孩子去上健保园
-ls that okay? -Sure. Is she married?
可以吗？ 当然可以，她结婚没有？
Are you jealous?
你嫉妒吗？
I just don't see why she has to play with you.
我不懂她干嘛跟你出去玩
I mean,doesn't she have any other stripper-mom friends of her own?
她没有其他当妈妈的 脱衣舞娘朋友吗？
You are totally jealous!
你嫉妒得要命
I'm not jealous.
我才没有嫉妒
This is about...
这是因为…
... people feeling certain things...
人们对脱衣舞娘…
...you know,about...
都有某种…
...strippers. And,you know....
看法，你知道…
I love you too.
我也爱你
Bye.
再见
Wait,wait,wait!
等等…
What?
干嘛？
Well,there's a kiss he won't forget for a few hours.
这个吻可以让他 回味好几个小时
Either that or you just turned him on and sent him to a stripper.
否则，你刚煽起他的火来 反而便宜了脱衣舞娘
Is there a Julio here?
胡利欧在这里吗？
I am Julio.
我就是胡利欧
Mr. Pretentious
你非常自以为是
You think there's no one finer Your poems are unpublished
以为自己好得不得了 你的诗都没出版
And you work in a diner
你在餐厅工作
You're no God's gift to women That's all in your head
你不是上帝对女人的恩赐 这只是你自以为是
You are just a butt-munch
你只是个马屁精
No one likes a butt-munch!
没人喜欢马屁精
And you're also bad in bed
你的床上工夫也很烂